

Christian De Leon DevOps Engineer

Orlando, FL USA

DevOps Engineer with 4+ years of experience in designing, deploying, and optimizing infrastructure as code with AWS. Highly motivated and always working above the baseline of expectation by continuously pushing myself to learn new and complex systems and technologies.

Visit my Portfolio @ https://christiandeleon.me - https://github.com/christian-deleon - https://linkedin.com/in/christian-de-leon93

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jun 2018 - July 2022 | Remote

NDA - Independent Contract - Full Stack Developer

Worked with a private investor as a sole developer to research and develop applications to analyze and make investing recommendations

- Developed highly redundant, high-throughput, time-sensitive, and event-driven micro-services using IaC as Terraform,
 AWS CDK, CloudFormation which build and deploy services such as AWS EC2, ECS, Lambda, Step Functions,
 EventBridge, DynamoDB, API Gateway, and SQS to process and analyze up to 10,000 messages a second
- Used Kubernetes and AWS Batch with Fargate and EC2 to run one billion simulations where the results were extracted, transformed, and saved using Redis, AWS SQS, RDS MySQL, Lambda, Step Functions
- Used Jenkins and AWS CodePipeline with CodeCommit, CodeBuild, and CodeDeploy as the CI/CD
- Built user interfaces and charts to control services and analyze data using Prometheus, Python, Pandas, Matplotlib, and React.Js
- Developed Machine Learning Models and Deep Reinforcement Agents to assist in classifying, tracking, and predicting market trends

Dec 2020 - Dec 2021 | West Palm Beach, Florida

Shoot Straight

- Receive and process firearm shipment
- · Restock firearms and accessories
- Receive or ship transferred firearms
- · Install and troubleshoot store IT infrastructure
- Educate employees and customers on firearm safety

Oct 2019 - Dec 2020 | Miami, Florida

Miami-Dade County Public Schools

Material Handler / Developer / IT Support

- Develop logistics applications using Visual Basic to aid in the weekly delivery of testing material for 500+ schools
- Track all inbound/outbound testing material
- Prepare testing material for shipment to all MDCP Schools
- Research and develop new methods of delivery, tracking, and organization

SKILLSET & TOOLSET

AWS (CDK, CloudFormation, CodePipeline, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, Lambda, EC2, ECS, ALB, ASG, API Gateway, Step Functions, RDS, DynamoDB)

Terraform, Kubernetes, Docker, Ansible, Prometheus, Python, Bash, Git, SQL, Redis

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified:

- DevOps Engineer Professional
- · Solutions Architect Associate
- SysOps Adminstrator Associate
- · Developer Associate

HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD)

(In-Progress) Certified Jenkins Engineer

(In-Progress) Prometheus Certified Associate

EDUCATION

2020 - 2021

Southern New Hampshire University Completed 63 hours towards B.S. in Computer Science

2016 - 2019

Florida International University Completed 78 hours towards B.S. in Mechanical Engineering

2011 - 2016

Miami Dade College

A.A. in Mechanical Engineering

2007 - 2011

Christopher Columbus High School High School Diploma